export const chapter = "Chapter - 8: First Empire";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Who founded the Nanda dynasty and ruled Magadha before the rise of the Mauryan Empire?",
        optionA: "Ashoka",
        optionB: "Chandragupta Maurya",
        optionC: "Mahapadma Nanda",
        correctAnswer: "Mahapadma Nanda",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the European king who attempted to conquer the Indian subcontinent in 326 BC but turned back without attacking Magadha?",
        optionA: "Alexander the Great",
        optionB: "Chandragupta Maurya",
        optionC: "Porus",
        correctAnswer: "Alexander the Great",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What were the three primary sources of information about the Mauryan rule mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "The Indica, the Arthashastra, and the Mudrarakshasa",
        optionB: "The Mahabharata, the Ramayana, and the Vedas",
        optionC: "The Upanishads, the Bhagavad Gita, and the Manusmriti",
        correctAnswer: "The Indica, the Arthashastra, and the Mudrarakshasa",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who guided and trained Chandragupta Maurya in various aspects of statecraft, helping him become a powerful ruler?",
        optionA: "Ashoka",
        optionB: "Porus",
        optionC: "Chanakya",
        correctAnswer: "Chanakya",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the title earned by Chandragupta Maurya after defeating the Nanda rulers?",
        optionA: "The Great Liberator",
        optionB: "The Emperor of Bharat",
        optionC: "The Conqueror of Magadha",
        correctAnswer: "The Emperor of Bharat",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which neighboring kingdom did Ashoka the Great conquer after the devastating Kalinga war?",
        optionA: "Magadha",
        optionB: "Ujjain",
        optionC: "Kalinga",
        correctAnswer: "Kalinga",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did Ashoka embrace after the Kalinga war, leading to a significant change in his attitude?",
        optionA: "Jainism",
        optionB: "Buddhism",
        optionC: "Hinduism",
        correctAnswer: "Buddhism",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What term is used in the text to describe the doctrine of non-violence promoted by Ashoka?",
        optionA: "Aryanism",
        optionB: "Ahimsa",
        optionC: "Dhamma",
        correctAnswer: "Ahimsa",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which language was commonly used to inscribe Ashoka's rock edicts?",
        optionA: "Greek",
        optionB: "Sanskrit",
        optionC: "Pali or Prakrit",
        correctAnswer: "Pali or Prakrit",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What led to the decline of the Mauryan Empire within 50 years of Ashoka's death?",
        optionA: "Efficient administration",
        optionB: "Strong military",
        optionC: "Opposition to Buddhism and non-violence",
        correctAnswer: "Opposition to Buddhism and non-violence",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Nanda dynasty was founded by ______________ before the rise of the Mauryan Empire.",
        optionA: "Chandragupta Maurya",
        optionB: "Mahapadma Nanda",
        optionC: "Ashoka",
        correctAnswer: "Mahapadma Nanda",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Alexander the Great entered the Indian subcontinent in 326 BC and defeated King ______________ between the rivers Jhelum and Chenab.",
        optionA: "Chandragupta Maurya",
        optionB: "Porus",
        optionC: "Mahapadma Nanda",
        correctAnswer: "Porus",
      },
      {
        question:
          "We know about the Mauryan rule mainly from three books: the Indica written by Megasthenes, the Arthashastra written by ______________, and the Mudrarakshasa written by Vishakhadutta.",
        optionA: "Ashoka",
        optionB: "Chandragupta Maurya",
        optionC: "Chanakya",
        correctAnswer: "Chanakya",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Chanakya guided and trained Chandragupta Maurya in various aspects of ______________, so that their dreams could be realized.",
        optionA: "Religion",
        optionB: "Statecraft",
        optionC: "Warfare",
        correctAnswer: "Statecraft",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Chandragupta Maurya earned the title of 'Emperor of Bharat' in 321 BC and was known as ______________.",
        optionA: "The Great Liberator",
        optionB: "The Conqueror of Magadha",
        optionC: "The Emperor of Bharat",
        correctAnswer: "The Emperor of Bharat",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Chandragupta turned towards the north-west after defeating Seleucus Nicator and expanded his empire. Seleucus Nicator governed the territory that Alexander the Great had left after his invasion and appointed his governor in ______________.",
        optionA: "India",
        optionB: "Greece",
        optionC: "Egypt",
        correctAnswer: "India",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mauryan Empire extended from Bengal in the east to the Hindu Kush in the west, and from the Himalayas in the north to the ______________ in the south.",
        optionA: "Ganges River",
        optionB: "Narmada River",
        optionC: "Yamuna River",
        correctAnswer: "Narmada River",
      },
      {
        question:
          "After Chandragupta, his son Bindusara became the emperor and ruled from 297 BC to 272 BC. Bindusara is said to have maintained friendly relations with other ______________.",
        optionA: "Dynasties",
        optionB: "Empires",
        optionC: "States",
        correctAnswer: "States",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Ashoka the Great ascended the Mauryan throne in 272 BC and earned titles like Devanam Priya (beloved of gods) and Priyadarshi (handsome-looking) after his coronation in ______________.",
        optionA: "269 BC",
        optionB: "261 BC",
        optionC: "272 BC",
        correctAnswer: "269 BC",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mauryan empire declined within 50 years of Ashoka's death, in 185 BC, when Pushyamitra Sunga overthrew the last Mauryan king due to various factors, including opposition to ______________.",
        optionA: "Jainism",
        optionB: "Buddhism",
        optionC: "Hinduism",
        correctAnswer: "Buddhism",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The Earth's uppermost layer is called soil.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Soil is not essential for the growth of plants.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Humus makes the soil less fertile.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Weathering is the process of rocks breaking down by the action of wind, water, and climate.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The characteristics of soil depend on the types of animals that live in it.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Alluvial soil is most fertile when found in the Ganga valley.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Black soil is mainly found in the Northern Plains of India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Red soil gets its color from the iron found in its composition in a crystallized form.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Yellow soil appears when red soil is dehydrated.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Soil's characteristics are not influenced by factors like temperature and rainfall.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
